Emmanuel!
(God With Us - Matthew 1:23)
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I know God has an assignment for me.
When I was coming I kept asking God, what was I going to do?
I didn't know what I was coming to do.
At this time the Lord said to continue to go.
I'm here Lord, I'm waiting for my assignments.
Viewers all over the world, I believe God has positioned you because if you are positioned you receive.
First you need to be positioned.
I believe you are positioned.
(Amen.)
Say, “I have been positioned for healing, deliverance, salvation and prosperity.
I have been positioned. Thank You, Jesus!”
That is the first thing.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I was asking God to give me the Bible verses and the one He directed me to...
I was asking God - this one is talking about the treasure in the church.
He said: No, that treasure in the church means the needy.
So, we take our reading from that Book of Mark 12 verse 41.
The widow's offering.
Are you here?
"Jesus sat down opposite the place where the offerings were put
and watched the crowd putting their money into the temple treasury.
Many rich people threw in large amounts.
But a poor widow came and put in two very small copper coins, worth only a few cents."
You know what copper coins mean - worth only a few cents.
"Calling his disciples to him, Jesus said,
'Truly I tell you this poor widow has put more into the treasury than all the others.
They all gave out of their wealth;
but she, out of her poverty, put in everything - all she had to live on'."
I will call this an assignment from God.
This is an assignment from God to you.
Today, we all believe we can only give out of abundance.
Ask the poor widow and she will tell you that everyone has something to give.
Big or small, everyone has something to give.
In things both great and small, everyone has something to give.
Jesus cares so much about little things.
Tell your neighbour.
(Jesus cares so much about little things.)
I can't hear you
He cares so much about your cent, your penny
He knows the number of hairs on our heads and He cares for a single sparrow that falls.
It is quite easy to give what our life depends on, what we cherish most, with little than when we have much.
When you have little, it is easy to give.
Whatever you give out of little means a lot to you and attracts God's attention.
Good example: you have just 5 dollars.
Whatever you give out of that 5 dollars means a lot to you and attracts God's attention.
More than giving a million dollars.
If you had one million dollars, you wouldn't know how much of it to give.
One million dollars is one million responsibilities.
If you don't know how much you need God in small things,
you cannot know how much you need Him in bigger things.
You don't know how much you need God to sit down.
When you want to sit down, you believe you can sit down without God.
This is the problem of all of us have today.
When you want to sit, you just sit down.
Not a single person can stand up to tell me: "Before I sit down, I rely on God's strength".
"In the name of Jesus", before I sit down - no.
You believe you can do that on your own.
If you don't know how much you need God in small things,
you will not know how much you need Him in bigger things.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You don't know how much you need God to laugh.
You will not know how much you need God to set you up from affliction.
So, you believe you can sit on your own, you don't need Him to sit,
you don't need Him to stand, you don't even need Him to laugh, you don't need Him to walk -
you walk freely on your own, you talk freely on your own
but when trouble comes, you say: "God, I need you. God heal me. God bless me."
God is constantly putting us to the test in the small things.
If you fail to bless others with the little blessing God has given to you, more may never come.
If you fail to appreciate God with the little blessing you have, more may never come
because if you don't appreciate Him in the little things,
you may not know how to appreciate Him in the bigger things.
It is easy to give God our quality time when we are nobody.
Quality time means there's no time that you cannot give God.
When you are nobody...
It is easy to give quality strength when we are nobody.
So, in the same vein, it is easy to give what our lives depend on, what we cherish most
when we're nobody than when we are somebody.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
At your level now, you cannot give your quality time, what your life depends on what you cherish most -
the best of you.
When will you give your best?
When you become more important...
That time may never come.
That is what Jesus was talking about.
He said, "Look at the poor widow giving what her life depends on".
It does not mean we have to give all, but the little we part out of a little means much
and attracts God's attention.
She had little and she parted with little out of the little.
But out of abundance...
You know the reaction of the rich man, when he was asked to sell all his possessions.
He said he did not know where to start from.
"I don't know where to start from."
If you don't know how much you need God to talk, walk, smile, greet, dress up,
you will always have a certain occasion for prayer.
Because you believe you don't need God to walk.
That is why you have a certain occasion for prayer.
You believe you don't need God to sit - that is why you have such an occasion for prayer.
You believe you don't need God to dress up - that's why you have a certain occasion for prayer.
And a break in prayer is a break in faith and a break in faith is a break with God.
We don't know how much we need God; that is why we have certain occasions for prayer.
When you know how much you need God -
the Bible says, 'Pray without ceasing, pray continuously'.
When you know you need God to walk, talk, greet, sit, dress up,
you will not have a certain occasion for prayer -
prayer all the time; prayer without ceasing.
Your life, success, happiness, progress, depend on your willingness to help others.
Your progress in life - I mean your happiness and joy
depends on what?
Your genuine willingness to do what?
(To help others.)
To help others - to help the poor, needy.
How much you help the poor is how much you progress.
How much you help the needy is how much you succeed.
If you say you have little, more may never come;
it's too little to part with, it's too little to give out of, more may never come.
God cares so much about little things.
Tell your neighbour.
(God cares so much about little things.)
He cares so much...
That is why he was watching the poor widow.
Instead of looking at the rich, He decided to watch the poor widow.
He cares so much about little things, how we manage little things.
Tell your neighbour.
(He cares so much about little things, how we manage little things.)
I can't hear you
How you manage your little possessions, how you manage your little money.
He cares so much because more may never come.
Tell your neighbor.
I can't hear you.
He cares so much and is concerned about us.
Oh, my people, it is easier to part with little than much.
Tell your neighbor: "Oh, my people, it is easier to part with little than much."
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Take note of that.
You say, "I have little...".
Oh, this is a message from God to you.
For you to have peace, you need to be concerned about people around you.
Your life depends on your willingness to help.
Your joy and happiness depend on your willingness to bless others.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Take your pen and write this: "God cares so much about little things - little possessions, little money."
What you call "little money"?
"Little money" is just enough for your daily bread for your family.
That little - how you manage it; because more may never come.
That is why some people remain poor till now and keep complaining -
because of the way they manage the little they have.
Take note of many families or people you knew in the past - they remain poor or they get poorer.
You look at them - they keep complaining about being poor and they keep getting poorer.
This affects the children.
Many families live this way - many of them have to give their children up for adoption.
They see slavery because of poverty.
Tell your neighbour: "They see slavery because of poverty".
"I have just little, that was given to me" - God is concerned about that little so much
because more may never come.
Why God is concerned about that little?
Because more may never come - that is why He is concerned.
This little - more may never come.
For more to come, you have to be ready to part.
Help the needy, help the poor.
If you say you are poor, there are others that are poorer.
We always have people that have less than us.
If you say "I'm very poor", you will always see poorer than you.
There are always people that have less than us.
Yes, if I'm talking to you ,let me see your hand.
Always.
When you say, "I'm very poor" - when you look, you will always find someone poorer.
If you say you are very sick, when you look around, you will see one that is more sick.
Someone is always there who needs what you have.
Tell your neighbor: "Someone is always there who is in need of you"
God is always concerned; He wants you to grow.
There is a new day every morning - you just have to grow.
Because of how you manage your little possession, money, He is always concerned
because more may never come.
As you help, someone is there to help you.
The more you help, the more they help you.
The more you help someone who is in need of you, someone is there to help you.
Someone is waiting to help you, when you help others.
Tell your neighbour: "Someone is waiting to help you when you help someone who is in need of you
but when you remain dormant, refusing to help,
someone who is waiting to help you will also remain looking at you.
What you are looking for, someone has it.
God has sent someone to help reshape your destiny
and that someone is waiting for you to help someone who is in need of your help.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Thank you.
Bless you!
(Amen!)
So now, it is a gracious thing for you to know that someone is waiting for you, for your help.
Someone is waiting for your support.
Someone is waiting for your prayer.
Someone is waiting for what?
Can you talk to me?
You know that someone is waiting for your help and someone also is waiting to give you.
As you help, you receive.
(Amen!)
Thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
This is a physical structure.
You are the Church; build people!
Go and build people; don't build the churches.
This is a physical structure, a building.
You are the real Church the Bible is talking about.
Church will build you; you can build church.
They should talk more about how to build humans - manpower.
What message are you taking home?
Can somebody stand up and tell me the message you are taking home?
Brother... thank you.
Everyone has something to give.
Thank you.
If you don't know how much you need God in a small thing,
you will not know how much you need God in a bigger thing.
God cares so much about little things.
For more to come, part with them - help the needy.
Thank you. Clap for him.
Anyone else?
Two lessons I am taking with me.
First one: "God cares so much about little things".
The second one: ...
That is God cares so much about little things.
And that "little things" is an idiom.
- Yes.
- OK.
What do you understand about the "little things", sir?
It can be your possessions...
- Thank you; little possessions.
- Little possessions.
- Thank you.
- The little money you have.
Thank you; clap for him.
Did you listen to that?
God cares so much about little things.
That little means...
He is talking about average, less privileged.
What we consider as little?
Why is He so concerned about it?
Because we must manage it very well.
For this little to become big, we must be ready to give out of that just like the poor widow
because more may never come.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
And it is very, very easy to give with little.
You can give a quality one with the little you have, but it is very difficult to give quality with much.
You remember the rich man, for whom it was difficult to sell his possessions.
He said he hadn't known where to start from.
Because you can only give what you do not need.
If rich men want to give, they always give what they do not need.
If you met the millionaires, the rich - if you met them...
If Jesus met them, what they would do - they would open their garages.
Things they are going to give are not those they are using now.
These are things they have packed for many years.
They are still good, but they don't need them anymore.
The rich always give what they do not need, but the poor give what their lives depend on.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You want to say something?
Come on!
One message I'm taking from here; I must know that there is always somebody who is in need of me.
... who is in need of me.
No matter how little you have, someone is in need of you.
Tell your neighbor, "No matter how little you have, someone is in need of you."
No matter how little you have, no matter how little money you have,
no matter how little possession you have, someone is in need of you.
I have also learned that we usually give quality time to God when we are nobody.
Thank you.
But when we are somebody, then we don't have quality time for God.
Did you listen to that?
When we are nobody...
When we say nobody, maybe you just see yourself belonging to your family, work place or your church.
If anything happens to you, when you are little, your church will care, your family will cry,
people at your working place will worry.
These are the people who know you.
But when you become so known all over, and you become big and famous,
it is always so difficult to give out of abundance and riches - so difficult.
Unless you have been giving when you were little...
When you give while you are little, when you become bigger,
you will continue to give according to God's instruction
but when you say, 'Until I become bigger before I will start giving', more will never come.
If God wants to promote you, He will promote you for the needs of others.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You know; there are two promotions - God's promotion and devil's promotion.
"As I have given the money, not as the world gives them."
The world can give you money, possessions, promotion but not as God gives.
God gives with peace and joy.
There are conditions attached to satanic, demonic promotion, which one will pay dearly for.
You are saved to save others.
You are blessed to bless others.
If you are not ready to bless others, there is no need to bless you.
The condition to bless you is to bless others.
If it is not in your agenda to bless others -
God knows your hearts and He knows what will happen next.
You own now and God owns tomorrow.
If God knows you will not be there for the poor and the needy, more will never come.
Tell your neighbor: "If God knows you will not be there for the needy, poor, widows and orphans,
more will never come".
Thank you, sir.
Sit down.
Take your pen and write it down - I think this is good for you.
If God knows you will not be there for the poor, orphan, widow and widower, more will never come.
That is why many of us are still struggling with our poverty and hardship.
We keep praying to be rich for many years, but yet, no blessing
because you don't part with the little you have.
If you don't know how much you need
God in small things,
you will not be able to know how much you need Him in bigger things.
Thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
RV: Mel Flowers 17/03/2019